# **MUFAZZAL HUSSAIN**

Front End Developer | 7 Years

Email: <a href="mailto:h.mufazzal@gmail.com">h.mufazzal@gmail.com</a>
Phone: +91-738 748 6776

## **Professional Summary**

Expert in design and development of **Front End** along with web service integration. Fully proficient in **JavaScript**, **ReactJS** and **jQuery**. Self-Motivated and **Agile** development professional worked in full Application development life-cycle. Background includes Native Android, PHP development as well.

#### Skills

- ReactJs, Redux, JavaScript, jQuery
- HTML, CSS, bootstrap, ES6.
- NodeJS, webpack, npm.
- Angular 4/5/6 fundamentals

- Android Native, Android SDK, Eclipse.
- Web Services, Restful, Xml, Json.
- GIT, SVN.
- Agile, JIRA, confluence, HPQC.

## Work History

### **Accenture** | SSE - Front End Developer

Dec 2015 - Current

- UI development with ReactJs, HTML, CSS and JavaScript for multiple browser to match the requirements expectation.
- Debugging, testing and defect resolution of application and completing the target for delivery.
- Development of customized React component for re-usability
- Migration of code architecture form local state management to Redux.
- Configuration of Build process and optimization of imported component for faster performance.
- Worked in an Agile-driven environment to effectively maintain project timelines and utilize available resources.
- Application maintenance and L3 support for delivered application on PROD environment.

#### **Zensar Technologies** | *SE - Front End and Mobile App Developer*

Jan 2014 - Dec 2015

- Conceptualize, develop, and test Native Android applications, including UI, core functionality, and third-party SDKs
- Development of hybrid application for Android and IOS devices
- Configuring the application for different screen size and resolutions also maintaining backward compatibility
- Translated design team's UX wireframes and mock-ups into responsive, interactive features, using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, jQuery
- Coordinating with offshore team for different processes and release plans.

#### **Cuelogic Technologies** | SE - Android Developer

May 2012 - Jan 2014

- Conceptualize, develop, and test native Android applications, including UI, core functionality, and third-party SDKS
- Developed and tested over 12+ high-quality Android App that included animations, social networks, and server-side integrations and third-party support.
- Feature enhancement and defect fixing in existing project
- Writing well modularized, maintainable and reusable code to meet legacy support as well.
- Developed the cutting-edge user interface with animation and customized layout component for intuitiveness.
- Crated a framework with integration of PHP web service to expedite the development and integration of web service with client app.
- Time estimation and feasibility check for new requirements.

#### Adisoft Pvt. Ltd. | ASE - PHP Developer

May 2011 - Apr 2012

- Designed, development and testing of end to end web application for given requirements.
- Managed and maintained development of PHP back-end for dynamic database driven websites.
- Customization of different WordPress theme and plugin as well as development of WordPress plugin.
- Development and customization of Joomla CMS for meeting the client requirement.
- Development of website and dynamic web application with core PHP.
- Time estimation and feasibility check for new requirements.

### Training and Internship

## **Pnestec Systems Private Limited |** *TSE - PHP Developer*

Sep 2010 - Jan 2011

- Designing HTML template from mock up files
- Debugging and defect fixing in Joomla K2 component
- Customization of Joomla CMS for client specific requirements

### Accomplishments

- Developed the test report analysis tool to analyze the HTML formatted selenium report, which bring down many manual efforts and expedite the report analysis by 80%.
- In progress: Developing the Redux tool to configure and Action and Reducer by user interface which can reduce the time for boilerplate code.
- Took over the financial-domain project in strictly small timeline which include multiple JS-framework Reactjs and angular.

## Education

B. E. | Electronics and Telecommunication

2010

IET DAVV Indore, MP

HSC | Science 2005

Govt. Boys Higher Secondary School Barnagar

SSC 2003

Vivekananda High School Barnagar

### Personal Detail

Current Address -

B1, 801 Khushboo exotica, Kashid Park, Jawakar Nagar, Pimple Gurav, Pune – 411061

Permanent Address -

14/1 Abbas Tayyab ali gali no. 3, Barnagar, Ujjain, MP – 456771.

Passport Detail -

K7852195 | 23-08-2023 | Bhopal

## Declaration

I hereby declare that above information is correct to the best of my knowledge and belief.

-Mufazzal Hussain